How to delete a node from Dublin could last.
Consider this.
Double the injured list contains three nodes.
The first one contains data 100.
The second one contains number 200 as data and 300 in the third.
The algorithm behind deleting a note from the link at list says that you need to create two pointers
the first them the temp and the head is already create, so temp is referred as the same position to
that.
And if we are the stamp, is that data that we are searching for to delete.
So if we are going to delete 100 or then node that contains 100, then it is the first node we have
found it.
The first thing that you need to search for the note that contains 100.
And if you find it, then the steps behind deleting as follows, we move the cursor from here.
If there's a head.
And Stamp is founding the 100.
Then we remove the binding by changing that 2000 that following know that it is next to that found it
or that note that we are going to delete to null.
This is the first step we break the.
Connection.
The second step is freeing, so we delete the note by use free a free method and see and we are going
to implement this.
Java So don't worry, we are going to see everything in real life and in real programming.
So the first one, how to how to make it encoding.
Create a void delete node method.
And that contains two party meters, the head and the key.
So it's the pointer of the head and the key now create if have the equal equal to null, then return.
It is to one and then struck note stamp equal to hat.
Go and create a temporary pointer that that is at the hat because we need to start searching for the
double leading kit list for that given key.
So key here in the perimeter of the lead node method, you present the data of the node that we are
going to delete and in this case that we have seen the animation, it was 100.
So we have deleted the node that contains the 100 astate.
In order to search the list and find this.
Note that we are going to delete.
We need to go through a wide loop.
So while damp does not equal to null and temp does not equal or temp, the next point the data does
not equal the key, then temp equal temp, not next.
If we are searching for 100 and if there's not contained in all the data of the nodes, then it will
return.
But how to move that cursor?
We use temp equal temp the next in this loop.
We are going to go and pass through.
All the nodes are contained inside this double link, at least.
Until reaching them equal to none or temp data does not equal the key.
Now.
If 10 equal equal to null, then print, if he not found, if we have reached the end of the list and
we didn't find the key, then it is the key not found we are.
They are going to delete like 400.
A note that contains 400 and in this and in this linked list, there is no note that contains 400 gay.
LCF stamp equal equal to the have now had equal points out of the next.
So we moved there, had pointed to the next one to that before we have deleting the delete the note
and then head off the previous equal equal to null.
We are specifying that moved had cursor to it, the node that we have moved, the had cursor to it with
that the previous is equal to none.
And then we free that time by deleting that temporary and that cursor and the node that we are referenced.
OK.
LCF temp, the next equal, equal to null, then AMP.
Previous Next.
Equal to null and free temporary delete the note.
OK?
This is the case that we have created.
OK, so we have four cases if stamp equal equal to none.
Or else if that stamp equal to the head that we have seen we have had, we have to delete 100 from the
beginning of the note.
So this is the case is the first one.
And as if stamp the next equal, equal to null, we have reached the end.
Then previous equal next null and then free temp.
We have to delete the first that that last one and.
The fourth case is damp.
Previous Next.
Equal attempt at next and make that damp next.
Previous.
Equal to temp.
And then delete that temp and then note that it's referring to it.
OK.
It's very simple.
We have four cases.
If temp equal equal to none.
If we didn't find the key that we are searching for to delete the second case, if temp equal equal
to the had.
That we have searched and we are searching for that key.
That it is at the first one.
Or the third case, if them the next equal equal to none.
Then we are deleting or searching for a we have found it a temporary variable or we have searching for
ET note.
And we have found it at the end of the list.
So the temp the next equal to none, then make this and the first step, if it is in the middle, then
make deletion of the previous equal quote in the next and the next equal to their previous.
OK.
It's very simple.
By practicing, we can make everything good and we will see them in the coding and that in the programs
that we are going to create.